In the next few videos, we'll talk about large scale machine learning.
在接下来的几个视频里 我们会讲大规模的机器学习
That is, algorithms but viewing with big data sets.
就是用来处理大数据的算法
If you look back at a recent 5 or 10-year history of machine learning.
如果我们看近5到10年的机器学习的历史
One of the reasons that learning algorithms work so much better now than even say, 5-years ago,
现在的学习算法比5年前的好很多
is just the sheer amount of data that we have now and that we can train our algorithms on.
其中的原因之一就是我们现在拥有很多可以训练算法的数据
In these next few videos, we'll talk about algorithms for dealing when we have such massive data sets.
在接下来的几个视频中 我们会讨论这些运用大量数据的算法
So why do we want to use such large data sets?
为什么我们喜欢用大的数据集呢?
We've already seen that one of the best ways to get a high performance machine learning system,
我们已经知道 得到一个高效的机器学习系统的最好的方式之一是
is if you take a low-bias learning algorithm, and train that on a lot of data.
用一个低偏差的学习算法 然后用很多数据来训练它
And so, one early example we have already seen was this example of classifying between confusable words.
早先看到的一个例子是区分易混淆词组
So, for breakfast, I ate two (TWO) eggs and we saw in this example, these sorts of results,
在这个例子 早餐我吃了两个(TWO)鸡蛋
where, you know, so long as you feed the algorithm a lot of data, it seems to do very well.
我们知道只要你给算法很多训练的数据 它就能做好
And so it's results like these that has led to the saying in machine learning that
由于这些结果所以在机器学习领域有一个说法是
often it's not who has the best algorithm that wins. It's who has the most data.
通常不是最好的算法胜出 而是谁有最多的数据
So you want to learn from large data sets, at least when we can get such large data sets.
所以我们想用大的数据集 至少在我们可以得到大数据集的情况下
But learning with large data sets comes with its own unique problems, specifically, computational problems.
但训练大的数据集也有它自己的问题 特别是计算量的问题
Let's say your training set size is M equals 100,000,000.
假设我们的训练集的大小m是100,000,000
And this is actually pretty realistic for many modern data sets.
这对于现代的数据集其实是很现实的
If you look at the US Census data set, if there are, you know,
如果我们看美国的人口普查数据集
300 million people in the US, you can usually get hundreds of millions of records.
美国有3亿人 我们通常会得到上亿的记录
If you look at the amount of traffic that popular websites get,
如果我们看一下很受欢迎的网站的浏览量
you easily get training sets that are much larger than hundreds of millions of examples.
我们很容易得到至少上亿条的记录
And let's say you want to train a linear regression model, or maybe a logistic regression model,
假设我们要训练一个线性回归模型 或者是逻辑回归模型
in which case this is the gradient descent rule.
这是梯度下降的规则
And if you look at what you need to do to compute the gradient,
当你在看需要些什么来算梯度的时候
which is this term over here, then when M is a hundred million,
也就是这边的这个项 当m是一个亿的时候
you need to carry out a summation over a hundred million terms,
你需要加一亿个项
in order to compute these derivatives terms and to perform a single step of decent.
来计算这些导数项和计算一步的梯度下降
Because of the computational expense of summing over a hundred million entries
用求一亿个项目总和的计算量
in order to compute just one step of gradient descent,
来计算仅仅一步的梯度下降
in the next few videos we've spoken about techniques
在接下来的视频里我们会讲
for either replacing this with something else or to find more efficient ways to compute this derivative.
把这个算法换掉的或者是找一个效率更高的算法来算这个导数
By the end of this sequence of videos on large scale machine learning,
在这一系列讲大型的机器学习的视频后
you know how to fit models, linear regression, logistic regression, neural networks and so on
我们会知道如何拟合模型 线性回归 逻辑回归 神经网络等等
even today's data sets with, say, a hundred million examples.
包括上亿数据的例子
Of course, before we put in the effort into training a model with a hundred million examples,
当然 在我们训练一个上亿条数据的模型之前
We should also ask ourselves, well, why not use just a thousand examples.
我们还应该问自己 为什么不用几千条数据呢
Maybe we can randomly pick the subsets of a thousand examples
也许我们可以随机从上亿条的数据集里选个一千条的子集
out of a hundred million examples and train our algorithm on just a thousand examples.
然后用我们的算法计算
So before investing the effort into actually developing and the software needed to train these massive models
在我们投资精力和开发软件来训练大数据的模型之前
is often a good sanity check, if training on just a thousand examples might do just as well.
往往作为一个很好的检查是去看看用一千个数据是否合适
The way to sanity check of using a much smaller training set might do just as well,
来检查小一些的数据集是不是好用
that is if using a much smaller n equals 1000 size training set,
也就是说用一个小一些的m等于1000的训练集
that might do just as well, it is the usual method of plotting the learning curves,
通常的方法是画学习曲线
so if you were to plot the learning curves and if your training objective were to look like this,
如果你画了学习曲线而且你的训练目标看上去像这样
that's J train theta.
这是J_train(θ)
And if your cross-validation set objective, Jcv of theta would look like this,
如果你的j交叉验证集的目标 J_cv(θ)看上去像这个
then this looks like a high-variance learning algorithm,
这看起来像高方差的学习算法
and we will be more confident that adding extra training examples would improve performance.
我们会对增加训练集的大小来提高性能更有信心
Whereas in contrast if you were to plot the learning curves,
而相比之下如果你画的学习曲线是这样的
if your training objective were to look like this, and if your cross-validation objective were to look like that,
你的训练目标是这样的 你的交叉验证是那样的
then this looks like the classical high-bias learning algorithm.
这看起来像经典的高偏差学习算法
And in the latter case, you know, if you were to plot this up to,
在后一种例子里 如果我们把这个画到
say, m equals 1000 and so that is m equals 500 up to m equals 1000,
m等于1000 和当m大于500小于1000的时候
then it seems unlikely that increasing m to a hundred million will do much better
看上去增加m到上亿会不一定会好很多
and then you'd be just fine sticking to n equals 1000,
我们继续用m等于1000就很好了
rather than investing a lot of effort to figure out how the scale of the algorithm.
而不是花很多精力去找出这个算法的规模
Of course, if you were in the situation shown by the figure on the right,
当然 如果你的情况是如右图所示
then one natural thing to do would be to add extra features,
一个很自然的方法是多加一些特征
or add extra hidden units to your neural network and so on,
或者在你的神经网络里加一些隐藏的单元等等
so that you end up with a situation closer to that on the left, where maybe this is up to n equals 1000,
所以最后你会变成一个像左边的图 也许这相当于m等于1000
and this then gives you more confidence that trying to add infrastructure to change the algorithm
这给你更多的信心去花时间在添加基础设施来改进算法
to use much more than a thousand examples that might actually be a good use of your time.
而不是用多于一千条数据来建模 会更加有效果
So in large-scale machine learning, we like to come up with computationally reasonable ways,
所以在大规模的机器学习中 我们喜欢找到合理的计算量的方法
or computationally efficient ways, to deal with very big data sets.
或高效率的计算量的方法来处理大的数据集
In the next few videos, we'll see two main ideas.
在接下来的视频里 我们会看到两个主要的想法
The first is called stochastic gradient descent and the second is called Map Reduce, for viewing with very big data sets.
第一个叫做随机的梯度下降 第二个叫做映射化简 来处理大数据集
And after you've learned about these methods, hopefully that will allow you to scale up your learning algorithms to big data
在学习完这些方法后 希望这可以帮助你的学习算法处理大数据
and allow you to get much better performance on many different applications.
并且让你在不同的应用上有更好的表现 【教育无边界字幕组】翻译：teddypear 校对/审核：所罗门捷列夫